Shuhel Ahmed

Sylhet, Bangladesh Email: shuhel@ymail.com

Github: http://github.com/ahmedshuhel

Summary

- Full-stack software engineer offering 10+ years of experience working in a variety of environments with a breadth of programs and technologies.
- Extensive experience in Agile Development, Test-Driven Development, Domain-Driven Design, Object-Oriented Design, Service Oriented Architecture.
- Experience in building high traffic web applications and APIs, large-scale data processing systems on the AWS Platform.
- Proven track record in providing technical leadership.

Key areas

Enterprise Applications, Agile, Databases (SQL/NoSQL), JavaScript, Test-driven development (TDD/BDD), SPA, Domain Driven Design, CQRS, Event Sourcing, Design Patterns. REST, SOA, MVVM, MVP, MVC, User Experience.

Technology Stack

Client Side: JavaScript, React, AngularJS, Aurelia, DurandalJS, Winforms.

Server Side: Python, .NET, Node.

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB

Programming Language

Language	Level	Known since
Python	Professional	2013
JavaScript	Professional	2007
C#	Professional	2005
Typescript	Intermediate	2014

Experience

2016-Present

Tech Lead & Enginnering Manager NewsCred Inc.

- Led effort in re-writing and improving core product area in Content Marketing Platform in ReactJS from AngularJS.
- Developed NewsCred for Sales, an ABCM system, that helps the Sales Department engage with Leads and Opportunities via content.
- Developed an internal tool for tracking original content budgets, improving the productivity of the Editorial team by more than 70%
- Developed tools to measure Content Marketing maturity of customers, improving efficiency in deployment and program adoption.

- Modeled an automated data pipeline which aggregates data from various sources to AWS
 Redshift and then created data visualization to understand/analyze the trends, usage
 patterns, etc.
- Wrote services and APIs on AWS EC2 using Django REST Framework, Flask, NodeJS, MySQL, and Elasticsearch, automated infrastructure management using Ansible, built CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins.
- Decomposed an existing monolithic system into a microservice architecture to achieve stability and scalability.
- Lead and guide engineering teams to design scalable systems and cooperate with the Product Manager to plan and schedule.
- Managing 4 software engineers as an engineering manager and assisting them to grow in the organization.

2012-2016

Senior Software Engineer C&E Software Solutions Ltd.

- Developed an ERP solution for one of the largest government organizations with over 150000 users. The system manages 820 units located across the country and over 250000 people. The solution consists of several modules like HRM, Accounting, Training, Result Processing, Stock & Inventory, Ration Management, POL Management, Point of Sale, etc.
- Led the development effort of the company's flagship product, Hospital ERP. This complex system consists several sub-modules including OPD, IPD, Nursing Station, Admission, Emergency, OT, Day Care Center, Diagnostic Center, Follow Up and Prescription, MRD, MIS, and Accounting, Billing, Payroll, HRM, etc.
- Implemented a visual query builder and a search platform that operates on a highly denormalized data repository containing a huge volume of data.
- Wrote scaffolders in PowerShell and a helper framework that cut down the development time from 6/7 days to 5/6 hours for developers.
- Led a team of 5 engineers and provided training on TDD/BDD, CI/CD and frameworks like AngularJS, Angular Material, ASP.NET MVC, etc.

2010-2012

Independent Developer PosCube

- Designed and developed a restaurant management system (RMS) and integrated online order processing system that is being used by over 150 UK restaurants. The system is designed and optimized for POS hardware.
- Build an MVC framework for WinForms with SPA like experience and used in the application.
- Designed and developed a tablet-based companion application to take dine-in orders.
- Developed an online ordering system for restaurants.

2008-2010

Software Engineer C&E Software Solutions Ltd.

- Developed C# and WinForms applications that record sales, monitor inventory, keep customer ledger, and bill customer for a drinking water plant and distribution company.
- Designed and Developed a utility billing software for supermarket/shopping centers using C#, .NET, and Winforms.

Education

Metropolitan University - Sylhet, Bangladesh, 2008 B.Sc., Computer Science & Engineering

Open Source

- Core team member of Aurelia Framework
- Contributed to <u>Aurelia (https://github.com/aurelia/framework)</u>, <u>JSPM (https://github.com/jspm/jspm-cli)</u>, SystemJS Builder, Fluent Migrator, Humanizer, etc.

Hobbies and Interests

- Contributing to open-source projects.
- Reading code on Github, reading/learning the history and evolution of programming languages.
- Movies and Music.